## Marco Predari

Software Engineer focused on ship robust and good quality software.

⊕ Milano, Italy, CET

predorock.github.io / predorock@gmail.com / +393336823157



### **About**

Hello there, here's Marco, 10 years of experience as **Software Engineer** in the software industry. I headed my career path to **Software Architect** roles in start-ups and in consultancy. I think to be the missing piece for companies aiming to create great quality products without sacrificing productivity and delivery.

Based in Milan, but frequently around the Globe, I've great experience in Remote working even before pandemic.

Last, but not least, I'm an incredible bartender. Why is that relevant? Company events can be funnier than ever expected, isn't it?

## **Work Experience**

Greenovation Remote 2024 - Present

#### Tech Lead

Developed a suite of web simulators that assist customers in enhancing energy efficiency in residential properties, leading to significant cost savings.

# Spindox Labs - Ublique Remote Cloud & Integration Architect

2023 - Present

Leading technical architecture and infrastructure of the Ublique software platform.

- Designed a new cloud infrastructure leveraging microservices architecture, Terraform, and Kubernetes on AWS.
- Designed a set of ansible playbook boilerplates to make the software setup easy and fast for our internal team.
- I collaborated with the Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning team to build reliabile software and hardware infrastructures for our customers.
- Worked alongside pre-sale and solution managers to support the customer acquisition.
- Created data integration patterns to import the customer data quickly.

## Spindox Labs - Ublique Remote

2023 - 2022

#### Tech Team Lead

Leading a group of four devs responsible to develop and maintain the core of ublique platform (Java microservices)

- Design a new pipeline and versioning system for CI/CD with jenkins.
- Develop a new set of Gradle plugins to standardize the developer experience and the working agreement implementation
- Created an integration system to communicate with third part Artificial Intelligence algorithms in order to include advanced and custom feature from AI inside the Ublique platform

**Spindox** Hybrid 2020 - 2022

#### Fullstack Developer

Part of a Chapter team, I have worked on many project of the company

- Used Angular Components to create a set of reusable components. The library has been widely used in all the 3 teams working for the customer.
- Led the team to the adoption of the Monorepo Pattern for Angular2 projects.
- Restored a old mobile application with deprecated code and framework to a Ionic based mobile app. I have also designed a new set of Azure pipelines to manage CI/CD of the mobile app.
- Developed Cordova apps to manage Microsoft Dynamics CRM data.

1000TA / Jarvis 2018 - 2020

#### Cordova Developer

· Mobile Developer for smart home mobile app to perform energy analisys on business buildings.

Horsa Remote 2016 - 2020

#### Cordova Developer → Fullstack Developer

- Developed Mobile applications based on cordova and Ionic.
- Early adopter of the Google Firebase Platform and Cloud Run.
- Design a custom role engine (Java Drools) for employees satisfaction analisys.

Digitag 2015 - 2016

#### Fullstack Developer

- E-Commerce Software Developer with wordpress and prestashop.
- Developed taylor made software solutions for the art auction market.

Foowd freelance 2013 - 2014

#### Fullstack Developer

• Created a E-Commerce based on Elgg framework for gorceries social buying.

BigThink intern 2013 - 2014

#### **Angular Developer**

- Developed AngularJS applications for the Facebook app market.
- Design and conribute to the company framework to fast devliver fullstack applications (Laravel, AngularJS).

## **Education**

## Università degli studi di Milano

2007 - 2010

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Music Science

## **Skills**

JavaScript TypeScript React/Next.js Node.js Bun Java Gradle Kubernetes Terraform

Ansible AWS ECS EKS AWS Lambda Docker Podman Git Bash Linux Administration

## Certifications



## **Projects**

## **Ublique**

Ublique is a decision support system composed of a suite of vertical solutions created to help managers in the design and management of complex systems and processes.

Tech Lead Architect React Java Micronaut AWS

Terraform Docker K8S